Let's say that we wanted to write a custom class that represented the GitHub repositories
that we did in our final exercise and introduction to Python.
So our final exercise, let me open up that file quickly.
So if we remember in our final exercise, we created a query and then we got back this list
of items from the GitHub API.
And then we looped through all the results, which is a dictionary.
And we got the language, we got the number stars, we got the name, and we printed this
out.
How could we refactor this into a custom class?
So the first thing we would want to do is make a class called GitHub repo.
And we would want to create a constructor here.
And what are the variables that we would take here?
No languages, right?
The repo has a single language, right?
So this is each repository.
So it would take a name, a language, and the number of stars that it has.
And then we would just assign these values to the instance.
If I wanted to take this print out here, the string, and make it so that it's available
on every instance of my GitHub repo class, what method would I want to put it in?
This nice human readable print out, right?
And not just string, but what?
I don't understand.
And that also takes the self.
We don't need any of the other variables because we know that they're attached to the
instance.
And we want to return a string here, right?
And use self.name, self.language, and self.stars.
So I'm going to run this file again in this interactive mode.
And now I can make a new GitHub repo.
And again, even though these are required variables, I can provide names here if I want
to.
So let's say this is view.
And the language is JavaScript, and the number of stars is 50,000.
I want to save this into a variable.
Why are we seeing this here when we make a new GitHub repo?
I'm not a generator.
I only implemented star, but I didn't implement what other method.
Repper?
Repper.
And when we enter this instance into the repo without a print or anything like that,
it uses the repper.
Now that I've assigned a variable view, I can double check that assumption.
If I ask for the repper, it's that.
And keep in mind, for those kind of built-in types, the zip, the range.
If you see something like that, it means that it might be a generator.
It's not guaranteed.
But if you see this for your own custom classes, it means that you forgot to implement
star or repper.
But now if we look at the star of you, oh, sorry.
I mean a mistake here.
It's a num star.
And I'm just going to copy this into the file so that I can just run a view here.
Under the hood, print a call star, because we're using print when we want to represent
to the user, and star is the one that is the user friendly one.
So I'll run that Python file in the terminal, oops, have to you.
For some reason, my VS code terminal just is not happy, so I'm going to delete that one.
And run it again, and there we go.
We'll see that view is a JavaScript repo with 50,000 stars.
So this is how we start encapsulating some of the data we've been working with.